Brothers and Sisters of the Southwest District Alumni Association,

After a few days of thinking it out, I have decided to announce my candidacy for the positions of Communications Director and Kappa Kappa Psi Member-at-Large in the Southwest District Alumni Association.

My name is Lea Sanchez. I am currently pursuing my Masters in Performance with a certificate in Arts Management and Entrepreneurship at the University of Oklahoma and I am a private clarinet teacher at Southmoore High School in Moore, Oklahoma.

I am a Life Member of the Alpha Chapter of Kappa Kappa Psi, graduating back in May 2022 at Oklahoma State University with a Bachelors in Music Performance, and I was initiated in the Spring of 2019 during the Centennial year. During my time as an Active, I was part of the Ritual and Social Committees for my chapter from 2019-2021. In my final year at Oklahoma State, I served as the chapter's Seargent-at-Arms and chaired the Jurisdiction Committee. I am currently on my final year of serving on the National Chapter Operations Committee for Kappa Kappa Psi, serving on the Parli Pro Subcommittee. I am also doing additional voluntary work for the OU School of Music which includes working on audition days and filling in for studio members in large ensembles. I continue to stay involved at my undergrad with the OSU Alumni Band.

For this being my first year in SWDAA, I have been amazed at the hard work our alumni association has done for our district. It has been a great experience serving on the Social and Communications Committee. I aim to continue the hard work and foundation our Board has set for our members. As an editor for SWDAA's letter "The Cadence", it has been great impact for our members to see how everyone is doing outside of SWDAA. I plan to continue bringing "The Cadence" to our members along with providing additional source tips for financial stability, mental health and other tips. For Kappa Kappa Psi Member-at-Large, I want to continue working alongside the Tau Beta Sigma counterpart in creating fun events for our members. I want to start inviting Active Brothers and Sisters to our events to not only talk about SWDAA but take part in our many activities hosted by SWDAA to continue increasing our membership.

If you have any questions about my platform for both positions, they will be located at the latter of my packet. Feel free to reach out to me at leaprodigy3987@gmail.com for any further questions.

Thank for your time and consideration,

lea Garchez

Leandra Sanchez

2920 Chautauqua Ave. Apt 5 Norman, OK 73072 (210)-739-3987 leaprodigy3987@gmail.com

Education

Master of Music in Clarinet Performance, University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK, August 2022-Present

- Primary Instructor: Dr. Suzanne Tirk, Associate Professor of Clarinet
 Bachelor of Music in Music Performance, Oklahoma State University, Stillwater,
 OK, 2018-2022
- Magna Cum Laude
- Primary Instructor: Professor Babette Belter, Professor of Clarinet

Teaching Experience

Private Clarinet Teacher, Southmoore High School, Moore, OK, Fall 2022-Present

 Duties: Instruct students at the high school level, assist students in preparation for the OKMEA All-State rounds of auditions.

Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, OK

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant for MUSI 1071- Single Reed Techniques (Unpaid), January 2022-February 2022

 Duties: Instructed the clarinet portion of Single Reed Techniques, provided lists of clarinet repertoire ranging from beginner to collegiate, introduced and lectured about the auxiliary clarinets, provided feedback on student playing videos.

Work Experience

Usher, The McKnight Center for the Performing Arts, August 2021-May 2022

 Duties: Oversee performances and provide an amazing experience for guests, create a professional experience for student recitals hosted by the Oklahoma State University Greenwood School of Music, ensure all rules and mask policies are followed by guests at the expense of the performers.

Notable Performances

- OSU Woodwind Honor Recital, Fall 2021 (Chamber)
- Masterclass with Dr. Michael Dean, Clinician, March 30, 2021
- Masterclass with Anthony McGill, Principal Clarinet, New York Philharmonic, October 11, 2019

Ensemble Experience

University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK

- OU Wind Symphony, August 2022–December 2022
- OU Lab Ensemble, September 2022-Present

Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, OK

- OSU Cowboy Marching Band, 2018-2021, Visual Section Leader (Fall 2021)
- OSU Symphonic Band, 2018-2019, 2021-2022 (Principal Clarinet, Fall 2021)
 World Premiere: Pathways by Danielle Fisher
- OSU Wind Ensemble, 2019-2020, 2020-2021, 2022
- OSU Concert Band, Spring 2021, Principal Clarinet
- Frontiers New Music Ensemble, 2020-2021
- OSU Symphony Orchestra, 2020-2022

Trinity University, San Antonio, TX

Trinity University Wind Ensemble, March 2018

Awards, Honors, and Scholarships

Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, OK

- OSU Cowboy Marching Band In-State Tuition Waiver Scholarship, 2018-2021
- President's Honor Roll, Fall 2018, 2021-2022
- Dean's Honor Roll, 2019-2020

Sigma Alpha Iota International Music Fraternity Inc.

- Sigma Alpha Iota Undergraduate Scholarship Recipient, Fall 2021
- Sigma Alpha Iota Collegiate Honor Award Recipient, Spring 2022

Affiliations

Kappa Kappa Psi National Honorary Band Fraternity, 2019-Present Sigma Alpha Iota International Music Fraternity Inc., 2019-Present National Association for Music Education (NAFME), 2018-2019



Contact

Phone

210-739-3987

Emai

leaprodigy3987@gmail.com

Address

2920 Chautauqua Ave

Norman, OK 73072

Education

2022-Present

M.M. Performance with a Certificate in Arts Management and Entrepeneurship

University of Oklahoma

2018-2022

B.M. Music PerformanceOklahoma State University

Expertise

- Canva
- Social Media Outreach
- Podcast Experience
- Chairing a Committee

Membership

- Active Membership Alpha Chapter;
 Kappa Kappa Psi (March 2019)
- Life Membership Alpha Chapter;
 Kappa Kappa Psi (January 2023)

Lea Sanchez

Candidate for SDWAA Communications Director & Kappa Kappa Psi Member-at-Large

"Be healthy and take care of yourself, but be happy with the beautiful things that make you, you."

-Beyoncé

Experience

Q 2021-2022

Seargent-At-Arms

Kappa Kappa Psi - Alpha Chapter

- Draft, revise and propose amendments for the chapter constitution during business.
- Chair the Jurisdiction Committee.
- Oversee the positions of each chapter officer.
- Establish and run a Jury Board as needed.

2021-Present

National Chapter Operations Committee Member

Kappa Kappa Psi

- Meet and discuss about Chapter Operations in Kappa Kappa Psi,
- Meet the charges given by the National Leadership.
- Serve in the many committees included in CHOPS, such as Parli Pro.
- Build presentations and secondary workshops to be presented during the National Leadership Conference by our Committee Chair.

2021-Present

SWDAA Communications Committee Member

Southwest District Alumni Association

- Propose ideas for topics and articles to be included in "The Cadence."
- Edit and proofread the final draft of "The Cadence."

2022 - Present

SWDAA Social Committee Member

Southwest District Alumni Association

- Propose ideas for monthly SWDAA social events such as Super SWDAA Bowl, Pumpkin Painting etc.
- Plan events surrounding the Southwest District Convention.



Platform

Communications Director

With the success of "The Cadence", I want to continue issuing this monthly newsletter with some simple tips on financing, budgeting, and mental health. There are plenty of resources at our disposal that I pull from each of the states in our district to add to this section of "The Cadence."

I started using Canva frequently for all my academic presentations and graphics for a community Instagram I've been running for a year and a half. I want to continue highlighting the accomplishments of our members, graduating seniors, and educators.

One of my main goals for the positions I'm running for include how to interact and collaborate with our Active Brothers and Sisters in the Southwest District. We can include a section in the New ALTO that talks about SWDAA involvement and our monthly newsletter.

Feedback is always appreciated when it comes to reaching out to our Actives and SDWAA members. I want to implement and anonymous Google Form during our general body meetings on what members want to see in our social media.

Kappa Kappa Psi Member-at-Large

Our district is one of the largest districts in both Kappa Kappa Psi and Tau Beta Sigma and it can be difficult to host in-person events. One of the charges set by both MALs is to host an in-person SWDAA social through interests and location via Google Forms. I went to plan and host at least one to two in-person events each semester for our members to attend to further embrace the bond of SWDAA Brotherhood and Sisterhood.

With the recent Super SWDAA Bowl event, I noticed that we had several members from other districts and Actives attending. With help from the Communications Director, I want to host district wide themed Zoom mixers with other districts. We only get to see Brothers and Sisters of other districts either at NLC or National Convention and I think hosting one of these mixers and other socials can strengthen our connection SWDAA has with other districts.

